Okay first we are going to need a lump of clay for the house itself.
I used between two and a half and three pounds of clay on that one so I am going to cut another piece about that size.
That is right at about three pounds and that is perfect.
Pat this into a nice good ball.
It always helps centering to make your piece into a nice good ball before you start.
Now next the lid it is a similar amount of clay probably closer to two and a half pounds and look there we happen to have it.
So we will pat that into a ball as well.
And finally we need some clay for this knob that we are going to make.
I don't weigh clay for the knobs.
I usually just take my hand and make a fist into the clay and that is the perfect amount of clay for a knob like that and we are ready to start throwing.